# YVETTE KONDOH

(469) 877-2546 • 121 E Tasman Dr., San Jose, CA 95134

yvetteekon@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/yvettekondoh • https://github.com/yvetteekon

### **RESUME SUMMARY**

A versatile data scientist with considerable experience in executing data-driven, action-oriented solutions to challenging business problems. An expert in developing credit scoring and credit recovery models in the domain of Agriculture and Finance, with a demonstrated ability to deliver valuable insights via data analytics and advanced data-driven methods.

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

SuperFluid Labs Accra - Ghana

# **Data Analytics Scientist (Remote)**

January 2018 - Present

- Performed comprehensive aggregate, cohort and comparative analysis of client data to quantify business problem and derived key insights from customer segments.
- Automated repetitive data science tasks to improve efficiency in model development. Automated scripts
  are continually being used in subsequent projects by the data science team consequently improving team
  efficiency.
- Led a project to successfully design and develop an initial credit scoring model using data from a digital
  wallet-based savings product. The project team successfully computed credit risk scores by defining and
  deriving features guided by the 5 C's of credit, from the raw data. Customer segmentation of the data
  generated key insights that helped the company uncover an anomaly in the design of the savings product
  and to also drive precision marketing.

# **Junior Data Analytics Scientist**

February 2017 – December 2018

- Performed statistical analysis on farmer profile, appraisal, loans and repayments data to quantify business problem of a small-holder farmer lending company.
- Developed a credit scoring model that was deployed in production. Model was able to successfully predict (recall) 79% of loans which were actually fully repaid (which is an improvement over the baseline of 72%) and would have helped avoid 21% of all loans that were actually overdue.
- A key speaker at a webinar on a real-life case study of a credit scoring model developed for a small-holder farmer lending company as part of a DataHack4FI initiative.

Jane Addams Resource Corporation

Chicago - USA

### **Data Analyst Intern**

May 2016 - December 2016

- Initiated the cleaning and data validation of existing spreadsheets. This improved data accuracy and reduced time for cleaning and analyzing data for the team.
- Trained employees on the use of pivot tables and tips and tricks in MS Excel for efficient data entry and analysis.

#### SKILLS

**Hard Skills:** Machine Learning Algorithms, Predictive Modeling, Statistical Methods and Analysis, Data Cleaning, Manipulation and Visualization, Mathematics

Data & Analytics Tools/ Languages: Python, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, Git, SQL, R, SAS

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Science: Applied Statistics,August 2014 - December 2015Loyola University ChicagoChicago - USABachelor of Science: Actuarial Science,August 2008 - May 2012Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and TechnologyKumasi - Ghana

### **CERTIFICATION**

SAS Certified Base Programmer for SAS 9 (BP064115v9)

October 2016

### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request.